<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DS on Mathematics Seminars List</title>
    <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/categories/ds/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DS on Mathematics Seminars List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020–2030, Jaume de Dios</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/categories/ds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stability and collapse of Oseledets spectrum for Perron-Frobenius cocycles</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/university-of-maryland_anthony_quas_16042020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/university-of-maryland_anthony_quas_16042020/</guid>
      <description>It is known, by work of Bochi, Mañé, Viana and others that Lyapunov exponents are highly sensitive to perturbations of a dynamical system. On the other hand, work of Ledrappier, Young and my work with Froyland and Gonz´alez-Tokman has shown that in some situations, under “noise-like” perturbations, Lyapunov exponents vary continuously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collatz Conjecture</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/matrix_terence_tao_14042020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/matrix_terence_tao_14042020/</guid>
      <description>Define the Collatz map Col on the natural numbers by setting Col(n) to equal 3n+1 when n is odd and n/2 when n is even. The notorious Collatz conjecture asserts that all orbits of this map eventually attain the value 1. This remains open, even if one is willing to work with almost all orbits rather than all orbits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attacking Classical Problems in Dynamical Systems with Descriptive Set Theory</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/ucla_matthew_foreman_10042020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/ucla_matthew_foreman_10042020/</guid>
      <description>In his classical 1932 paper, von Neumann asked 3 questions: Can you classify the statistical behavior of differentiable systems? Are there systems where time-forward is not isomorphic to time-backward? Is every abstract statistical system isomorphic to a differentiable system? These questions can be addressed with some surprising consequences by embedding them in Polish Spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>