<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mathematics Seminars List</title>
    <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mathematics Seminars List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020–2030, Jaume de Dios</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Sato-Tate and applications</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagebucur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagebucur/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing Sato-Tate and monodromy groups</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagezywina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagezywina/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arithmetic L-functions and their Sato-Tate distributions</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagesutherland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagesutherland/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circumcenter extension maps for Hadamard manifolds</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/osuincerti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/osuincerti/</guid>
      <description>Given a CAT(-1) space, we can associate to it a boundary at infinity and a cross ratio on said boundary. There is a series of results that tell us that, for sufficiently nice CAT(-1) spaces, the boundary together with the cross ratio uniquely determines the interior space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random walks on punctured convex real projective surfaces</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/columbiabray/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/columbiabray/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the following result, joint with Giulio Tiozzo: Letting $\Gamma$ be the representation of a punctured hyperbolic surface group in $PSL(3,R)$ acting discretely, properly discontinuously, and with finite co-volume on a properly convex set in the projective plane, we have that hitting measure for a random walk on any $\Gamma$-orbit with certain moment conditions is singular with respect to the classical Patterson-Sullivan measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Currents on Lubin-Tate space</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/columbiamihatsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/columbiamihatsch/</guid>
      <description>We will first give an introduction to the formalism of (p,q)-forms and currents on non-archimedean spaces, as defined by Chambert-Loir&amp;ndash;Ducros and Gubler&amp;ndash;Kannemann. We explain how a notion of Greens current can be used to reinterpret intersection numbers on p-adic formal schemes in their generic fiber; at least in some cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics of Active Gels: Bifurcations &amp; Stability</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/princetonberyland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/princetonberyland/</guid>
      <description>In this talk we present analytical studies of active gels and cell motility. We start from a brief overview of out-of-equilibrium active matter systems (e.g., active gels, bacterial suspensions, etc.) and mathematical challenges in their modeling and analysis.
Next we present three minimal models of active gels: a phase-field model and two free boundary models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Kudla-Rapoport conjecture</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/princetonli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/princetonli/</guid>
      <description>The Kudla-Rapoport conjecture predicts a precise identity between the arithmetic intersection number of special cycles on unitary Rapoport-Zink spaces and the derivative of local representation densities of hermitian forms. It is a key local ingredient to establish the arithmetic Siegel-Weil formula and the arithmetic Rallis inner product formula, relating the height of special cycles on Shimura varieties to the derivative of Siegel Eisenstein series and L-functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Pairs</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/seymourstanford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/seymourstanford/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;ldquo;pure pair&amp;rdquo; in a graph $G$ is a pair $(X,Y)$ of disjoint subsets of $V(G)$ such that either every vertex in $X$ is adjacent to every vertex in $Y$, or there are no edges from $X$ to $Y$. Let $f(G)$ be the biggest $k$ such that $G$ has a pure pair $(X,Y)$ with $|X|,|Y|$ at least $k$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramsey properties on infinite structures</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/siudobrinen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/siudobrinen/</guid>
      <description>Just how far can Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s Theorem on the natural numbers be pushed when, instead of coloring all k-sized subsets of the natural numbers, one is coloring copies of a finite structure inside some infinite structure? There is a host of results extending the finite Ramsey theorem to classes of finite structures, but much less so for the infinite Ramsey Theorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving inverse problems with deep learning</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/berkeleyying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 16:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/berkeleyying/</guid>
      <description>This talk is about some recent progress on solving inverse problems using deep learning. Compared to traditional machine learning problems, inverse problems are often limited by the size of the training data set. We show how to overcome this issue by incorporating mathematical analysis and physics into the design of neural network architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost all Collatz orbits attain almost bounded values</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/caltechtao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/caltechtao/</guid>
      <description>Define the Collatz map Col on the natural numbers by setting Col(n) to equal 3n+1 when n is odd and n/2 when n is even. The notorious Collatz conjecture asserts that all orbits of this map eventually attain the value 1. This remains open, even if one is willing to work with almost all orbits rather than all orbits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/caltechghomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/caltechghomi/</guid>
      <description>TBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress on the Erdos-Hajnal Conjecture</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/nccchudnovsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/nccchudnovsky/</guid>
      <description>What is the effect of excluding an induced subgraph on the global structure of a graph? While there do not seem to be general structural consequences, a conjecture of Erdos and Hajnal states that graphs with forbidden induced subgraphs behave very differently from general graphs; more precisely they contain much larger cliques or stable sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sato-Tate groups of abelian varieties of dimension up to 3</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagefite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/vantagefite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A p-adic monodromy theorem for de Rham local systems</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/uclashimizu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/uclashimizu/</guid>
      <description>Every smooth proper algebraic variety over a p-adic field is expected to have semistable model after passing to a finite extension. This conjecture is open in general, but its analogue for p-adic Galois representations, the p-adic monodromy theorem, is known. In this talk, we will explain a generalization of this theorem to etale local systems on a smooth rigid analytic variety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fraction of an Sn-orbit on a hyperplane</title>
      <link>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/berkeleypawloski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 12:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaume.dedios.cat/math-seminars/talk/berkeleypawloski/</guid>
      <description>Huang, McKinnon, and Satriano conjectured that if a real vector $(v_1,&amp;hellip;,v_n)$ has distinct coordinates and $n\ge3$, then a hyperplane through the origin other than $x_1+&amp;hellip;+x_n=0$ contains at most $2(n−2)!\lfloor n/2\rfloor$ of the vectors obtained by permuting the coordinates of $v$. I will discuss a proof of this conjecture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>